<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="background-senior-technician.xml" url="" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Senior Technician" type="Background" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_TANR_TECH_BACKGROUND_SENIOR_TECHNICIAN">
        <description>
            <p>Not many are able to devote as much blood, sweat, and grade points as you did to become a Senior Tech.  You're an expert in just about everything, including niche knowledge nobody really cares about or probably should even be thinking about.</p>
            <p><i>Yeah so technically this isn't actually NL-4 cable, it's a variety that we bough a long time ago before any of us were here, but the interesting thing about using it in place of NL-4 is that...</i></p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Arcana, History</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong>One of your choice.</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong>Two tech crew shirts, one polo, a pocket knife, a Scholar's Pack (a backpack, a book of lore, a bottle of ink, an ink pen, 10 sheets of parchment, and a little bag of sand.).</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Arcana, History, Language</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Senior Technician)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS_TEACH_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS_CONFUSE_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can’t help it— I’m a perfectionist.</item>
                <item id="2">I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.</item>
                <item id="3">Nobody stays angry at me or around me for long, since I can defuse any amount tension.</item>
                <item id="4">I hide scraps of food and trinkets away in my pockets.</item>
                <item id="5">I’m always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.</item>
                <item id="6">I take great pains to always look my best and follow the latest fashions.</item>
                <item id="7">I’m used to helping out those who aren’t as smart as I am, and I patiently explain anything and everything to others.</item>
                <item id="8">I’ve spent so long studying and doing homework that I have little practical experience dealing with people.</item>
                <item id="9">I am quiet and reserved, but observant. Nothing escapes my attention.</item>
                <item id="10">I quote (or misquote) sacred texts and proverbs in almost every situation.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Community. It is the duty of all people to strengthen the bonds of community. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Greed. I’m only in it for the money. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">People. I’m committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="6">Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1"></item>
                <item id="2"></item>
                <item id="3"></item>
                <item id="4"></item>
                <item id="5"></item>
                <item id="6"></item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I overlook obvious solutions in favor of complicated ones.</item>
                <item id="2">I speak without really thinking through my words, invariably insulting others.</item>
                <item id="3">In fact, the world does revolve around me.</item>
                <item id="4">I’ll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.</item>
                <item id="5">I’m a sucker for a pretty face.</item>
                <item id="6">Gold seems like a lot of money to me, and I’ll do just about anything for more of it.</item>
                <item id="7">I can’t keep a secret to save my life, or anyone else’s.</item>
                <item id="8">I throw myself and my friends into situations rarely ever thinking about consequences.</item>
                <item id="9">My desire to experience new things causes me to make unsafe choices.</item>
                <item id="10">I am overly protective of nature, sometimes to the detriment of my companions and myself.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Feature: Knowledge of The Ancients" type="Background Feature" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you are able to explain a technical concept to any creature that can hear and understand you, choosing to either confuse or teach:
            <ul>
                <li>If teaching, the next time the creature makes a skill check, ability check, or saving through, they add your ability modifier to their result. If you have proficiency in the check or saving throw, also add your proficiency or expertise bonus to their result.</li>
                <li>If confusing, the creature must make a (DC 12) Wisdom saving throw.  On a failed save, the creature becomes confused and has disadvantage on its next attack or saving throw.</li>
            </ul>
            You may only attempt this action on each creature once a day.
            </p>
		</description>
	</element>

    <element name="Knowledge of The Ancients: Teach" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS_TEACH_FEATURE">
		<sheet>
			<description>Target a creature that can hear you. The next time that creature makes a skill check, ability check, or saving through, they add your modifier and proficiency to their result. You may only attempt this action on each creature once a day.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <element name="Knowledge of The Ancients: Confusion" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOWLEDGE_OF_ANCIENTS_CONFUSE_FEATURE">
		<sheet>
			<description>Target a creature that can hear you to make a (DC 12) Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature becomes confused and has disadvantage on its next attack or saving throw. You may only attempt this action on each creature once a day.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>