<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
		    <file name="background-general-technician.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tanner-caffrey/techcrew-dnd/main/backgrounds/background-general-technician.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="General Technician" type="Background" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_TANR_TECH_BACKGROUND_GENERAL_TECHNICIAN">
        <description>
            <p>You've made it to General Technician after a few years, and all it might have cost you was your GPA, friends, and sleep.  You've got the job down by now and can do it all pretty quickly.</p>
            <p><i>I didn't become a Tech to gaff cable or lift JBLs-that's the PA's job.  If you need me, I'll be in the booth.</i></p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Arcana, Slight of Hand</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong>One of your choice.</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong>Two tech crew shirts, one polo, a pocket knife, a Scholar's Pack (a backpack, a book of lore, a bottle of ink, an ink pen, 10 sheets of parchment, and a little bag of sand.).</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DELEGATION" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Arcana, Slight of Hand, Language</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (General Technician)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DELEGATION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DELEGATION_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I thrive on esoteric lore.  The more obscure the historical references I can include in everyday conversation, the better.</item>
                <item id="2">I can barely go a minute without talking about my research. I have so much knowledge in my head, and it needs to be let out somewhere!</item>
                <item id="3">The spirits of the dead are so much interesting to talk with than living classmates.</item>
                <item id="4">I can speak eloquently about the historical ramifications of an ancient war.  But ask me to add two-digit numbers together, and I'm a mess.</item>
                <item id="5">In the end, it's all just entropy.  Everything falls apart someday.</item>
                <item id="6">I'm the life of the party, and I expect everyone's attention when I walk into a room.</item>
                <item id="7">Two weeks ago, I was enthralled with my latest project.  Now, I think it's garbage and deserves to be destoryed.</item>
                <item id="8">I believe everyone has the ability to express their truest selves through art, and I'm happy to quietly push them in the right direction.</item>
                <item id="9">Everyone is a critic, and I work to win them all over.</item>
                <item id="10">I'm beset with such an overwhelming sense of ennui regarding my studies or craft. Nothing quite captures my attention anymore.</item>
                <item id="11">Instead of confronting my negative emotions, I channel them into explosive artistic displays.</item>
                <item id="12">When I find a subject I'm interested in, I won't stop studying until I know everything about it.  It keeps me up at night.</item>
                <item id="13">I hope this all makes sense to me one day.  Until then, I'm going to keep faking it.</item>
                <item id="14">Equations and pattersn come naturally to my mind. I wish friendship came just as easily.</item>
                <item id="15">I believe I'm always the amrtest person in the room. And I'll prove it, even if no one asks me to.</item>
                <item id="16">If these classes have taught meeverything, it's that reality is a lie, and nothing matters.</item>
                <item id="17">Before I graduate, I want to achieve something impossible. I must leave a legacy!</item>
                <item id="18">I'll say whatever I need to in order to maintain my high social status.</item>
                <item id="19">I prefer saying the blunt truth over a petty lie, and I don't particularly care whose feelings I hurt.</item>
                <item id="20">I believe that uplifting my peers is the best way to succeed.</item>
                <item id="21">I've mastered the art of using humor as a defense, and I always have a charming joke ready.</item>
                <item id="22">I always wait before speaking, analyzing the situation for whichever angle is most advantageous to my goals.</item>
                <item id="23">No one knows about the all-nighters I've pulled to keep my magic looking effortless, and I'm going to keep it that way.</item>
                <item id="24">I love brewing up a new recipe, even if some might be repulsed by my choice of ingredients. Or the final product. Or both.</item>
                <item id="25">My fashion sense is like my garden,: withered, black, and weird.</item>
                <item id="26">I'm going to befriend every single monster in this swamp if it's the last thing I do.</item>
                <item id="27">Everything in this world dies eventually.  The question is, what will you do with the time you have left?</item>
                <item id="28">I know we just met, but when you die, may I have your bones? For research.</item>
                <item id="29">Don't interrupt me; I'm brooding.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Community. It is the duty of all people to strengthen the bonds of community. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Greed. I’m only in it for the money. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">People. I’m committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="6">Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)</item>
                <item id="7">Beauty. What is beautiful points us beyond itself toward what is true. (Good)</item>
				<item id="8">Logic. Emotions must not cloud our logical thinking. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="9">No Limits. Nothing should fetter the infinite possibility inherent in all existence. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="10">Self-Improvement. The goal of a life of study is the betterment of oneself. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1"></item>
                <item id="2"></item>
                <item id="3"></item>
                <item id="4"></item>
                <item id="5"></item>
                <item id="6"></item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I overlook obvious solutions in favor of complicated ones.</item>
                <item id="2">I speak without really thinking through my words, invariably insulting others.</item>
                <item id="3">In fact, the world does revolve around me.</item>
                <item id="4">I’ll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.</item>
                <item id="5">I’m a sucker for a pretty face.</item>
                <item id="6">Gold seems like a lot of money to me, and I’ll do just about anything for more of it.</item>
                <item id="7">I can’t keep a secret to save my life, or anyone else’s.</item>
                <item id="8">I throw myself and my friends into situations rarely ever thinking about consequences.</item>
                <item id="9">My desire to experience new things causes me to make unsafe choices.</item>
                <item id="10">I am overly protective of nature, sometimes to the detriment of my companions and myself.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Feature: Delegation" type="Background Feature" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DELEGATION">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can command a willing, friendly creature to take a single action.
            The action cannot involve moving more than 5 feet, unless you command them to only take movement; in which case the creature can move up to half its speed.
            If the creature successfully completes their action, you may add 1d4 to the result of one of your future rolls.
            This does not stack with subsequent successful actions i.e. you cannot stock up on additional d4 using this feature to add to a roll.</p>
		</description>
	</element>

    <element name="Delegation" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DELEGATION_FEATURE">
		<sheet>
			<description>Command a willing, friendly creature to take a single action. The creature can move up to 5 feet with the action, or up to half their movement speed as the action.
            If the creature successfully completes their action, you may add a non-stacking 1d4 to the result of one of your future rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>