<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Feats</name>
		<description>Feats from RIT Tech Crew.</description>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="feats.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Lucky Slacker" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_TANR_TECH_FEAT_LUCKY_SLACKER">
		<description>
			<p>You've never studied for sign offs, it took you five tries to pass your PA-12 sign off, and you only got the customer service sign off because you guessed the coordinator's number correctly with random numbers.  Honestly you don't know how you've made it this far, but you haven't gotten in trouble yet. Gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain proficiency in the Deception skill.  If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li><p>You have one luck point. Whenever you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can spend one luck point to roll an additional d20. You can choose to spend one of your luck points after you roll the die, but before the outcome is determined. You choose which of the d20s is used for the attack roll, ability check, or saving throw.</p>
                <p>You can also spend one luck point when an attack roll is made against you. Roll a d20, and then choose whether the attack uses the attacker’s roll or yours.</p>
                <p>If more than one creature spends a luck point to influence the outcome of a roll, the points cancel each other out; no additional dice are rolled.</p>
                <p>You regain your expended luck points when you finish a long rest.</p></li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Long Rest">
			<description>Whenever you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can spend one luck point to roll an additional d20. You can choose to spend one of your luck points after you roll the die, but before the outcome is determined.
			You can also spend one luck point when an attack roll is made against you. Roll a d20, and then choose whether the attack uses the attacker’s roll or yours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Sound Psion" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_TANR_TECH_FEAT_SOUND_PSION">
		<description>
			<p>You've trained your ear to become an expert at mixing and controlling soundscapes. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain proficiency in the Perception skill.  If you are already proficient in this skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                <li>You gain the ability <strong>Ears Raised</strong>:</li>
                <ul>
                    <li>You are able to discern the frequency of any sound you hear.</li>
                    <li>You know the location of any creature you can hear.</li>
                    <li>You are unable to be deafened against your will.</li>
                </ul>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Ears Raised">
			<description>
                You are able to discern the frequency of any sound you hear, know the location of any creature you can hear and are unable to be deafened against your will.
            </description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Absolutely Yolked" type="Feat" source="RIT Tech Crew" id="ID_TANR_TECH_FEAT_ABSOLUTELY_YOLKED">
		<description>
			<p>You've made serious gains solely through lifting our equipment. No joke, those spotlights are heavy. You can carry 6 chair at once, single-handedly lift YAM's onto sticks, and it's even been rumored you carried board board to the Ingle mezzanine all by yourself. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>When making a strength skill check, ability check, or saving throw, you may add 1d4 to your result, however on a failed check or saving throw, you take 1d4 damage, straining yourself.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
                When making a strength skill check, ability check, or saving throw, you may add 1d4 to your result, however on a failed check or saving throw, you take 1d4 damage, straining yourself.
            </description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>